Lucas Petherbridge

Senior Software Engineer

Passionate & driven polyglot software engineer with 12+ years experience designing innovative solutions using the latest software technologies and practices. Constantly seeking to expand and grow using modern technologies to create innovative solutions. Great communicator team collaborator, and mentor willing to take on any challenge.

Contact Info



Work Experience

Email

me@lukeworks.tech

Website

lukeworks.tech

GitHub

github.com/lukexor

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/lucaspetherbridge

Technologies

- Rust, Python
- JavaScript/Typescript, NodeJS, React/NextJS, HTML, CSS
- Actix, NGINX, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, CouchDB
- Docker, Kubernetes



Crossville, TN

Principal Software Engineer

Oct 2022 - Present

- Developed containerized software platform for Electromagnetic Spectrum Operations (EMSO) applications for the US Air Force using Rust, RabbitMQ/ZeroMQ, CouchDB, & Docker.
- Drafted an interoperability & portability specification for heterogeneous EMSO containerized applications using YAML & Google Protocol Buffers.
- Developed a container runtime system simulator for RF applications integrating with Software Defined Radios

Lithia Motors, Inc.

Portland, OR

Principal Software Engineer

Jan 2022 - Oct 2022

- Curated suite of libraries including a UI template & NPM package that increased project delivery speed by 10% using React, Typescript & NextJS.
- Led architecture initiatives for 7 teams, doubling website performance using LighthouseCI & PageSpeed Insights by migrating to NextJS.

Staff Software Engineer

Jul 2021 - Jan 2022

- Provided technical leadership to 6 teams by holding learning sessions, pair programming & writing extensive documentation using React & Typescript.
- Increased test coverage for unit & end-to-end tests from 0% to 60% using Jest & Cypress.

Senior Software Engineer

Jul 2020 - Jul 2021

 Developed customer authentication platform for an automotive e-commerce website using Auth0, React & Typescript deployed with Microsoft Azure & Kubernetes.



TEKsystems - Consultant at Nike

Beaverton, OR

Senior Software Engineer

Mar 2020 - Jun 2020

- Developed infrastructure as code for an AWS GraphQL API using Okta authentication & Terraform.
- Exit: Contract ended due to organization restructure.



NetFortris (Formerly Fonality, Inc)

Culver City, CA

Senior Software Engineer

Nov 2013 - Mar 2020

- Redesigned Salesforce integration plugin, reducing project size by 90% by switching from AngularJS to Vue.js.
- Developed an OSS/BSS for the ordering, billing, & provisioning of telephony services which led to a 20% increase in revenue using Perl, JavaScript, JQuery & HTML/CSS.



Education



Portland State University

Bachelor of Computer Science 2015 - 2019 · Portland, OR

 Provided Scrum & Agile Practice consultation services for 10 teams during my senior capstone.



Projects

PixEngine

Sep 2019 - Present

A cross-platform graphics & UI library for simple games, visualizations, & graphics application written in Rust. https://lukeworks.tech/pix-engine

TetaNES

Mar 2019 - Present

A cross-platform & web-browser emulator for the Nintendo Entertainment System (NES) written in Rust & Typescript supporting WebAssembly. https://lukeworks.tech/tetanes

Personal Portfolio/Blog

May 2022 - Present

A personal blog & project portfolio website using React/NextJS & Typescript. https://lukeworks.tech/